Detroit hit the road to Los Angeles for
a week 15 showdown with the one seed in
the NFC. It looked promising in the
first half for the Lions. Then Detroit
fell apart. The final from LA, Rams 41,
Lions 34. Welcome into the Detroit Lions
Live postgame show presented by Keiro
Auto Insurance. Alongside the Super Bowl
champ Lomas Brown, I'm Dannie Rogers.
Detroit is still in the playoff hunt,
but they don't control their own destiny
now. They're going to need some help.
Lomas, tonight Detroit hung 24 points in
the first half. Then they came out of
the locker room at half, they didn't
score in the end zone again until 3
minutes left in this ball game. What
changed?
>> you have to give the Rams a lot of
credit, Dannie. Their offense came out
and they kind of controlled the game if
you think about it. They had a I think
they scored on the next four drives,
maybe five drives, and we went three
plays and out. We didn't sustain drives.
And we knew coming into this game we
were going to have to limit the amount
of possessions that Matthew Stafford and
that powerful offense of the LA Rams
got. We weren't able to do that and it
really really hurt us
the second half of the game.
>> And one thing that won't jump out to you
about the final stat stats is the run
game for Detroit, non-factor. Just 70
yards on the ground. Rams total yards,
516. Meanwhile, Detroit held to 390
total offensive yards. Lions won the
turnover battle though. That INT in the
first quarter from Aidan Hutchinson, who
returned it 58 yards, but they couldn't
sustain that momentum. No, that and that
was a big play. You're right about that,
Dannie. What we needed to do was put
that in the end zone, but we weren't
able to do that. And then we again, we
knew we were going to have to match
score for score with these Rams because
of how good their offense was.
Um it was great that we were able to get
that turnover. Couple of penalties kind
of hurt us too in the second half that
kind of pushed us back. But the Rams,
you give them a lot of credit. They
really started attacking the middle of
our defense. And I thought that was kind
of the turning point. They got chunk
plays against us and we hadn't been
giving up those type of plays. And like
I said, it really came back to hurt us
in the second half.
>> Well, Detroit's secondary is still
banged up, down two starting safeties
and a starting cornerback and Terrion
Arnold. Head coach Dan Campbell is
standing by the podium. Let's hear from
him.
All right. Uh third quarter was was
rough on us, you know. Uh they got a
jump on us that we couldn't overcome. Um
you know, uh Nacua had a huge day. We
couldn't couldn't slow him down. Uh
you know, Stafford played
played at a really high level, which uh
we knew he would if we we couldn't
disrupt him. And more importantly, stop
the run. We weren't able to do that. Uh
you know, they they uh were able to
break through there and and grind it
out, which made it very difficult on us.
Uh and then
you know, we left three out there uh on
the field goal and uh
and then we didn't you know, we could
have scored touchdowns, man, you get in
a game like that. Knew we were going to
need some points and uh we weren't we
weren't able to
uh to get enough there. In third
quarter, we got to be able to stop the
bleeding offensively and uh we weren't
we never got our run game going.
Um
you know, I thought Goff, I thought
Saint, and Jamo played their tails off,
man. I I thought they were uh played a
really high level, gave us a chance. Uh
but we just weren't able to overcome
you know,
some of those things, you know. And uh
we knew that team didn't make mistakes.
Um
and and so it cost us. You know, we we
just weren't we couldn't do enough.
What's the message to the team after you
leave here? Do you believe any of the
games matters? Well, look, I don't even
know what happened. I mean, I just found
out after the game about Green Bay and
all that. So you know, my my message
don't go numb to to when you get these
losses, you know, the win lose win lose.
Like we we got to get out of that rut
and it can't be okay to well well, we'll
just Like it should it should burn at
you, you know, it should eat you up. And
do not go numb to the losing. All right.
Uh
Staff and I we're going to come in and
we're going to watch this thing together
tomorrow, all of us in all three phases.
Uh watch everything top down, the
players ourselves. Um
you know, and make those corrections and
then move on. And and and it's simple as
going back to work and we got to get
better with Pittsburgh coming into town.
We got to play better. And and now we
know
you know, now you have first-hand
knowledge of what
you know,
what probably the top of the NFC looks
like right now. That's that's them, you
know.
Um and so now you know, you know what it
looks like, you know what it is, and
we're not there right now.
Doesn't mean we can't be, but now we
know what it looks like. And uh you got
to get better. We got to get better. We
got to move on. Can't sulk about it.
Can't feel sorry for ourselves.
Um
we make the corrections and we move on.
Sorry about that.
What did happen in the third quarter
there? You guys went three and out three
and out three and out and they
didn't get you back in the game. Do you
especially in one play where
you had the pressure on most backs that
play to give up a sack? What
What did you kind of look at and
reassess what happened? Really, we
couldn't we couldn't I think more more
than anything we really just couldn't
get our run game going. That was going
to be important and that that one hurt
us, you know, we got a holding call
which made it difficult. Um
you know, some of those you're just
trying to get in third and five, you
know, and we were in third and 10, third
and long. Uh
you know, trying to run the ball, you
know, you get two yards and it just
makes it difficult. Um
we weren't over the you know, able to
overcome that. You know, I you can go
back well, maybe you should have just
thrown it and quit trying to do some of
those or you know, you go back and
forth. Um that'll be things that I look
at myself as to man, could I have done
this? Should I have done this better to
help these guys out? Um
But but the bottom line is we we weren't
able to convert. And so then we strung
the defense out and and then all of a
sudden it flips. You're up 10, you're
down 10. And uh it was it was that was a
rough quarter for us. Speaking of the
defense, 41 points and 19 20 yards,
that's coming off of a really good
performance last week. Is the first part
of it maybe just some of the
inconsistencies on on defense, one great
performance, one not, another one come
back kind of like just what you what you
talked about?
>> Yeah, wins and losses too. Yeah, that's
that's frustrating. Yeah, it's
frustrating. But it's also cuz we're
better than that. I know we're better
than that, you know. And look, I knew we
were going to need to score some points.
That's a good team. It's a good offense,
good quarterbacks, all of it, you know,
they got weapons. This 12's a hell of a
player, man. Uh
but but we're we're better than 41
points, you know. No, it's on the
scoreboard. That team over there earned
it. They put it up there, you know. So
you can't take that away from them, but
uh there's just little things, you know,
with some of the things fit in the run
we didn't do a good enough on the
perimeter. Uh
you know, everybody had a hand in that.
And then you know, once they're able to
run the ball with with what they've got,
it just makes it extremely difficult.
Extremely difficult. What went into the
decision to not attempt an onside kick
at the end of the game there when they
were running the ball as well as they
were?
Yeah, I I don't know.
I don't have an answer for you right
now.
Can you explain why? It just felt like,
you know, two timeouts and a two-minute.
Go ahead. Just can you explain the
challenge that you weren't able to
challenge and it cost you a timeout?
What you were told there and what led to
that in the first half I believe? Uh
they said I cannot challenge that
because it's not line the game.
But it was you know, I it was wrong. So
um
which they corrected.
So I won the challenge, but I lost my
timeout.
Um the the touchdown that was
called a touchdown on the field and then
reversed, what was the explanation they
gave That the call stands.
Did they say that he bobbled it on the
way to the ground? They said the call
stands.
Dan, through through three quarters you
only had three players who were targeted
for the catches. Um
do you feel you had enough variety in
your play calling or were you kind of
hamstrung by not being able to get that
running game going as well? Well, when
you can't get the run going it does it
it limits what you can do and what
you're trying to do off of it. I don't
regret one bit getting the ball to to
Saint Brown and Jamo. I have zero
regrets about that. Um
but we got to get the run game going,
you know, we got to be better and we can
be better.
Couple more guys.
Maybe you could just say the decision to
go for it on on the 29 there. You know,
big call at that point in the game got
led to a touchdown and then you get in
that lead. Just just had felt like that
was a time to do it.
>> Yeah, I just I I felt really good about
it, you know, I knew we'd get it. I felt
very confident about it and I knew the
players would execute. Um
and it just I I felt like we would have
the right look and it it worked out, you
know. If it doesn't then yeah, I'm in
trouble, right? So that's the
it's the story of every week. Back to
what you said at the beginning about you
know, you can't be numb to this. What is
the locker room sort of feeling when
they had so much success last couple
years?
>> well, look, I think they're they're like
anybody else, they're frustrated. They
don't like losing. I mean, these guys,
you know, that's
they don't. But but I go back to this
the core of this group are man, they're
the right guys, you know, and they've
been through this. I mean, most of those
guys know what the dumps looks like. And
we're not in the dumps, but they know
what that was like, you know, back to
back to back to back to back losses. And
you don't ever want to even get a taste
of that again. And uh
so it's just important that that nobody
gets that way or particularly young guys
cuz they don't know. Some of these guys
don't know any different. Rookies, uh
second-year players, especially if all
you've done is won.
Um you just don't want them to to ever
get into that mode of well, you just
playing for the next week, you know,
you're just kind of playing and
you're going through it. You're just
trying to make your own way and you
can't, man. You this thing has got to
burn at you and you you have to have
urgency to
to correct your errors. And we do
collectively as a team. Okay, so the
final objective have to go three and
three and oh to to finish here to to
make the playoffs. Just what's the
number one thing that gives you
confidence that this team can take I I
think I just I I just mentioned it, man.
The guys on this team. I believe in the
guys on this team.
The the character of the players on this
team, our captains, the core of it. And
uh
There again, we we we needed to play a
close to perfect game. We were not
able to play perfect enough, all right?
Um
we made too many errors against that
team, which some other teams we we would
have been enough. It's not against that
team. So,
um
but
I know we can do it. I mean, these these
players know we can do it. You go back
to work, man, you know? I I don't
believe for 1 second anybody's lost
confidence. We just know we're doing a
good job of taking care of the ball.
We're getting some takeaways. We need to
get a couple more. Um
and then we got to play for three
quarters, man. We got to play
high-level.
Excuse me, four quarters, but instead of
that third quarter that was a a stinker.
We we got to do it. Uh
you know, for four. So, we got three to
go here and
you know, we don't control our own
destiny, but but we need to win these
three and it starts with Pittsburgh at
home.
Jared Goff didn't have a good game.
Guys, your prior success has put you at
the top of the power rankings list.
That's a good thing, right? Well, just
means [music] you've gone from the
underdog to the favorite.
But those expectations come from prior
success. So, that's okay.
What about Cure? Where do you guys rank
on the power list? Actually, we just got
named by Forbes as one of the best car
insurance companies in America.
>> [music]
>> Now you're the favorite. Guess we have a
lot in common.
Go Cure. Go Lions.
Cure auto insurance. Drive well.
Detroit Lions Live is brought to you by
Cure auto insurance.
Log on to cure.com to see how you can
save.
Welcome back. It was an offensive chess
match in that first half. 518 total
yards combined between both the Rams and
the Lions. Jared Goff returns back home
to California, back to the team that
drafted him number one overall. Uh he
went 25 of 41 on the day. 111.6 rating.
Took a couple of sacks, but he took care
of the ball and he had some time to work
through most of this game in terms of
working in the pocket.
>> Oh, Jared gave us the opportunity to win
this game, uh Danny. He was point-on. He
spreaded the ball around. He got to the
ball to the receivers and his weapons
that he needed to get the ball to. So, I
I I think Jared played a very, very good
game coming back home to California.
Again, it was just too much Rams offense
for us tonight that really did us in. We
couldn't stop those guys, especially
like we talked about in the second half.
But I thought Jared did pretty good
comparatively speaking because we really
didn't have a run game like he normally
has to lean on. So, I don't look at
anything that Jared did that hurt us
tonight. He did as much as he could to
try to help us. Goff leaned on Amon-Ra
St. Brown, a fellow Cali kid here in the
passing game. Amon-Ra finished 164
yards, 13 receptions on 18 targets. His
longest catch of the day for 52 yards.
He is crisp with his route running and
his YAC. 60 yards after catch were
standout stats here tonight.
>> he had over 100 yards in the first half.
I mean, nine catches over 100 yards in
the first catches. So, you're right.
Amon-Ra did all he could to help this
offense out. Again, I thought Jameson
had a nice game, too. Jared did what he
needed to do to spread the ball to those
guys, get it get the the ball to them in
the position where they could run like
you saying get that YAC, that yards
after the catch. So, again, it's just
our running game that didn't hold up his
end of the bargain offensively to help
the rest of the team.
>> And just 70 rushing yards on the day.
Jared Goff also found Jameson Williams
in the passing game. Williams 18.0 yards
of catch today thanks to his uncanny
speed on the back end. He averaged 15.5
mph per route. That is the fastest in
the NFL and you saw him take it up a
notch here today. He did. I mean, he's
he knew the sense of urgency that we had
to play with and I thought he stepped up
just like Amon-Ra stepped up. Again,
just not enough guys in the offense to
help us out today. Normally, we're
getting catches from Jamaal Williams.
They kind of limited that and I know
these teams are looking at Jamaal
Williams trying to limit him not only in
the run game, but in the pass game, too.
But I thought those guys did a great
job. Our receivers are stepping up and
really providing nice targets for Jared
to be able to get the ball to. Over 334,
338 passing yards rather, from Jared
Goff. QB1 is standing by at the podium.
Let's hear from him.
offensively Yeah.
Yeah, the first down efficiency I think
is the main thing to point at. You know,
unfortunately it wasn't. I think we had
three drives and I think
one of them had like a 5-yard gain. The
other two were like one or zero on first
down and that's just tough. That defense
is is good and if you allow yourself to
be behind the sticks like that,
they do a good job. Now, we had our
chances to convert there on third down
and
um would have liked to get that done
still, but uh you you you lower your
your opportunities there when when
you're
starting and um behind the sticks like
that. It's yeah.
Do you feel like you got enough from the
run game today?
Um yeah, you always want to be better in
certain areas, certainly. Um yeah, I
think you know, those guys would say
that they'd like to do a little bit more
there in the run game and um I don't
think that's uh an indictment on
anything. I think that's just who we
are. We want to be able to run the ball
and
um yeah, there were certain times where
you wish you you could get a little bit
more, but listen, the games change.
Games games go certain ways where where
we run for 250 and
um the pa- the passing is a little bit
harder and so we we rely on each other
and today it was leaning on the passing
game a little bit more. Hey Jared,
8 and 6,
still still in it though. What are your
thoughts on overall where the team sits
now? 8 and 6, still in it. Got three
games left.
Uh would like to win all three of them.
Got to win the first one. You're
probably going to have to win all three
and maybe get a little bit of help, too,
to make the playoffs. Just what gives
you confidence that that you guys can
get on a stretch here to finish 8 and 9
with these last three? Yeah, we got a
resilient group, man. We we bounce back
after things like this and um got a home
game in front of our fans. Expect them
to bring it for us and
find a way to win that one and go to the
next and
it'd be nothing better than entering the
playoffs off a three-game win streak and
um
that's got to be the goal, but again, in
order to win three you got to win one
and so we got to focus on that one.
What was working for you guys
that allowed
to jump out to that lead?
Yeah, we were just uh
leaning on them a little bit. I I
thought there were there there were
certain runs that were that were really
good and then we were throwing it well.
Um guys were getting open. We were
protecting really well. Um giving me
some time there. I was able to get over
the top of them a couple times and
um yeah, it was it was a solid uh half,
but unfortunately it wasn't enough in
the second half for us. Jared, do you
have any personal feelings when you play
the Rams at this point? No.
How do you feel like that protection has
kind of uh evolved over the season,
particularly in the
last couple games here?
Yeah, you know, it's it there it's been
ebbs and flows. I think I think the last
few games have been really good. I
really do. I think, you know, certainly
in Dallas was was really good and I
thought today was was really good for
the most part as well. Um
giving me plenty time back there, able
to get over the top like I said. Some of
these in-cuts that we were able to hit.
Um I thought those guys did really well
up front.
We rarely see, I think, St. Brown and
Jamaal Williams were the only guys
targeted among wide receivers in the
first half. Just
what changed in the second half? Just
cuz they were cooking at a pretty wild
level in that first half there. Did they
change anything to stop those guys?
No. Um
I think again, if you look at those
drives, I believe there was three of
them
um or two or three, I don't remember,
but
you know, when you're in third and eight
and 10 it's hard and and it's hard to
you know, we want to be able to get in
All all it takes for us the first down.
That's what we always say. Get us that
first down, get us new statistics and
things tend to go from there and those
two guys are as explosive as anyone and
being able to get them the ball in space
is what we want to do and we did a good
job of that for the most part. You guys
called by Dan there leaving this second
quarter
20-19. He said, "Do you guys are going
to get it?" Just what was it about that
play? Was it just Yeah, good play we had
kind of working on all week and loved
the
uh the action there and and who it was
going to and and everything about it
with with the defense they were playing
and um
yeah, it was confident that one would
work.
But St. Brown, that was the second time,
I believe, you guys have scored with
that type of play in the last couple
weeks or what do you like about that
play in that situation? They kind of got
to have it on third down. Yeah, you
know, it's it's one of those where maybe
we're Dan is planning to go for it on
fourth.
So, if I I don't know where we were,
like third and five from the eight or
something, something like that. So, if
we were able to get to fourth and one,
probably go for it. So, it's it's a LA
Rams, Aidan Hutchinson picks off Matthew
Stafford. He was so instinctual on that
play, got into the passing lane, and ran
it back for 58 yards. That man almost
got a big man touchdown, but more
importantly, he needed some oxygen after
that.
>> Dani. That was a big play. If you think
about it, that set us up for our I think
our first score then. So, it was just a
nice job by Aidan, like you say,
recognizing that it was going Matthew
was trying to throw the screen, getting
up there, making the catch, and then the
yards after the catch were impressive.
So, again, nice job. He was able to get
in on several quarterback hits, got him
a sack today. So, I thought he played a
overall good game today. Again, just
needed more help from the other guys on
the side of the defense to help him out.
But, that was a big play, a big turning
point because the score was 0-0 at that
point.
>> Hutch ended the day with three
quarterback hits, a sack, three total
tackles, one pass defended. Detroit's
defense ended the day with seven passes
defended, but gave up too many
explosives when it counted, Loomis.
>> That's what killed us, Dani. You're
right, those explosive plays. I mean,
they counted for
uh big plays on the offensive side of
the ball. It It enabled uh LA to move
down the field with those explosive
plays. One was a 36-yarder, you had a
50-some-yarder. You just can't give up
those type of plays, especially in games
like this where both teams were just
tight. You know, statistically and
everything, and it was such a big game
where we knew it was going to be a play
or two, maybe a turnover or whatever, it
was going to be something small that
could swing the game.
>> Mhm. Detroit couldn't swing it back
their way in the second half. Coming up
next in our Detroit Lions Keiro Auto
Insurance postgame show, next matchup
including the Pittsburgh Steelers at
home inside Ford Field, and final
thoughts from this big guy. We'll be
right back.
Guys, your prior success has put you at
[music] the top of the power rankings
list. That's a good thing, right? Well,
it just means you've gone from the
underdog to the favorite. But, those
expectations come from prior success, so
that's okay. What about Keiro? [music]
Where do you guys rank on the power
list? Actually, we just got named by
Forbes as one of the best car insurance
companies in America. Now, you're the
favorite. Guess we have a lot in common.
Go Keiro. Go Lions.
Keiro Auto Insurance, drive well.
Detroit Lions Live is brought to you by
Keiro Auto Insurance.
Log on to keiro.com to see how you can
save.
After falling to 8 and 6 on the season,
Detroit will return home to face a very
familiar foe and quarterback Aaron
Rodgers and his Pittsburgh Steelers. We
won't see them take the field until
Monday night, Monday night football
against the Miami Dolphins. Detroit
knows Rodgers extremely well. How much
will they that benefit Detroit in this
matchup?
>> it'll benefit us a lot in that matchup,
Dani. You're right, being familiar with
Aaron Rodgers, what he likes to do. Now,
it's not the same Aaron Rodgers that we
faced when he was with Green Bay, but
he's a effective quarterback again. I
still think the uh key for us to get
that victory is we're going to have to
get hits, sacks, and pressures on Aaron
Rodgers, get him uncomfortable so he
can't find his favorite receivers or
find the guys that he's normally trying
to go to. So, it's going to be important
for us to play really, really solid
defense, but we're going to have to tie
the pass rush in with our pass coverage.
>> That week 16 matchup with the Steelers
will be a 1:25 kick inside Ford Field,
the final home game of the season. Lions
fans have got to bring it. We are. We
do. I mean, Dani, if you think about it,
we have to win I I say 11 games to get
in, so we're going to have to win these
next three games that we play, and we
can. I mean, we can. These are guys that
we're familiar with when you talk about
Pittsburgh and then Rodgers, you talk
about Green Bay I'm sorry, Chicago and
you talk about Minnesota coming up. So,
it's winnable games, but we got to go
out there and make sure we execute and
get these victories.
>> Urgency has a whole new meaning in
Detroit. Just three games left, Lions
will have to win out to even get a shot
at the playoffs here. Final takeaways
from LA, Detroit was cooking on all
cylinders there in the first half. What
do they have to do moving forward to
make sure they sustain that momentum?
>> Yeah, Dani, just really disappointing
that we couldn't sustain the momentum
that we had in the first half. We're
going to have to definitely change
things up in our secondary. I mean, you
could just kind of see the injuries are
really starting to hurt us. Our first
game without Brian Branch being back
there. He was our difference-maker, but
we're going to have to generate a way to
get these quarterbacks uncomfortable.
Matthew Stafford was too comfortable
tonight. He was able to look around,
find his guys, and make big plays. We're
going to have to shore that up a lot
more when we get ready to face
Pittsburgh next week.
>> will have a lot of time to think about
this loss and their upcoming opponent in
the Steelers, but a 5-hour plane ride
back home to Detroit in a very frustrat-
frustrating fashion, that is. The final
from Los Angeles, LA 41, Detroit 34.
Thanks so much for tuning in to our
postgame show, presented by Keiro Auto
Insurance. For Loomis Brown, I'm Dani
Rodgers. We're getting back on that
airplane. We'll see you all in Detroit.
>> [music]
[music]